This is it.
이것이다.
I can't die like this.
이대로는 죽을 수 없어요
I finally...
드디어...
I finally want to live...
드디어 살고 싶다...
as the real Lee Han Young.
진짜 이한영처럼
[Episode 1]
[1화]
The Seoul City Council has passed its 18th ordinance of 2035, aimed at
서울시의회가 가결되었습니다. 2035년 제18차 조례는 다음을 목표로 합니다.
improving urban aesthetics and public safety
도시 미적 개선 공공 안전과
by removing homeless people from the streets.
노숙자를 거리에서 몰아냅니다.
Under the ordinance, if homelessness is identified in major areas,
조례에 따라, 주요 지역에서 노숙자가 확인된 경우
police or private security officers
경찰 또는 개인 보안 담당자
are authorized to carry out immediate eviction.
즉시 퇴거를 수행할 권한이 있습니다.
It referred to as the "urban homeless removal system."
이를 다음과 같이 지칭합니다. "도시 노숙자 제거 시스템."
As a result, homeless people
그 결과 노숙자들
are being pushed into underground tunnels, abandoned buildings, and storm drains.
지하 터널로 밀려 들어가고 있습니다. 버려진 건물 및 빗물 배수구.
Human rights groups are pushing back, calling it an effort to erase people,
인권단체들이 반발하고 있는데, 사람을 지우려는 노력이라고 합니다.
not provide welfare.
복지를 제공하지 않습니다.
Three members of a family were found dead
일가족 3명 숨진 채 발견
in a semi-basement home in Hanyang City.
한양시의 반지하 주택
Inside the room with no electricity or running water,
방 내부에는 전기도 없고 물도 없습니다.
only a pizza box believed
피자 상자만 믿었습니다
to be the family's last meal was found.
가족의 마지막 식사가 발견되었습니다.
Police say the parents, driven by severe financial hardship,
경찰은 부모에게 이렇게 말했습니다. 심각한 재정적 어려움으로 인해
killed their young son
어린 아들을 죽였습니다
before taking their own lives.
자살하기 전에
The room was piled with
방이 가득 찼습니다
overdue bills and scrap paper,
연체된 청구서 및 파지
and the family's bank account was
가족의 은행 계좌는
reportedly empty.
비어 있는 것으로 알려졌습니다.
The tragedy has sent shockwaves through society,
비극이 보냈다 사회에 충격을 주고
as economic hardship
경제적 어려움
pushed a family to the brink.
가족을 위기에 빠뜨렸습니다.
[text]
[텍스트]
Gojin Chemical, acknowledge the industrial accident!
고진화학, 산업재해를 인정하다!
- Acknowledge it!
- 인정해!
Gojin Chemical, apologize to the public!
고진화학, 대국민 사과하라!
- Apologize!
- 사과하다!
The courts must punish Gojin Chemical!
법원은 고진화학을 처벌하라!
- Punish them!
- 처벌하라!
Gojin Chemical, acknowledge the industrial accident!
고진화학, 산업재해를 인정하다!
- Acknowledge it!
- 인정해!
Gojin Chemical, apologize to the public!
고진화학, 대국민 사과하라!
- Apologize!
- 사과하다!
No matter how harsh the world gets,
아무리 세상이 험난해도
what can they do if we follow the law?
우리가 법을 따르면 그들은 무엇을 할 수 있나요?
The guilty will be punished,
죄를 지은 사람은 벌을 받을 것이다.
and everyone here will get
그리고 여기 있는 모든 사람들은
their medical bills and compensation.
의료비 및 보상.
So...
그래서...
you should stay strong,
넌 강해져야 해,
and just take care of yourself.
그리고 그냥 몸조심하세요.
Got it?
알았어요?
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Oh, sir.
아, 선생님.
- Good to see you. - Yeah.
- 만나서 반가워요. - 응.
You've been through a lot.
당신은 많은 일을 겪었습니다.
Thank you. We're counting on you.
감사합니다. 우리는 당신을 믿고 있습니다.
The courts must punish Gojin Chemical!
법원은 고진화학을 처벌하라!
- Punish them!
- 처벌하라!
Gojin Chemical, acknowledge the industrial accident!
고진화학, 산업재해를 인정하다!
- Acknowledge it!
- 인정해!
Dogs bark the loudest when they're scared.
개는 겁을 먹었을 때 가장 크게 짖는다.
We've handled this before.
우리는 이전에 이 문제를 처리한 적이 있습니다.
So don't worry.
그러니 걱정하지 마세요.
Gojin Chemical, acknowledge the industrial accident!
고진화학, 산업재해를 인정하다!
- Acknowledge it!
- 인정해!
Gojin Chemical, acknowledge the industrial accident!
고진화학, 산업재해를 인정하다!
- Acknowledge it!
- 인정해!
No dogs bark in a courtroom.
법정에서는 개가 짖지 않습니다.
Gojin Chemical, apologize to the public!
고진화학, 대국민 사과하라!
- Apologize!
- 사과하다!
S Construction, step down!
S건설, 물러나라!
- Step down!
- 물러나세요!
Guarantee our right to survive!
우리의 생존권을 보장해주세요!
- Guarantee it!
- 보장해요! - 보장합니다!
S Construction, step down!
S건설, 물러나라!
Father?
아버지?
[text]
[텍스트]
- Are you ready? - Yes.
- 준비됐나요? - 예.
Yes.
예.
All rise.
모두 일어나세요.
[text]
[텍스트]
[Kim Jin Ah, Prosecutor] As we arrive, lock it down top to bottom.
[김진아 검사] 도착하면 위에서 아래로 잠그세요.
If we miss even one piece of paper, they'll hit back immediately.
종이 한 장이라도 놓치면 즉시 반격을 가할 것입니다.
Then we're screwed.
그러면 우리는 망한 것입니다.
I see. [Kang Jae Jin, Prosecutor]
알겠어요. [강재진 검사]
I'm swamped. Why now?
나는 푹 빠졌다. 왜 지금?
[Central District Prosecutor]
[중앙지검장]
[Ma Kang Gil, Chief Prosecutor] - That idiot is really picking a fight now?
[마강길 부장검사] - 그 바보가 지금 정말 싸우려고 하는 겁니까?
They're probably getting ready.
아마 준비 중일 거예요.
[text]
[텍스트]
They'll be there shortly.
곧 도착할 것입니다.
Got it.
알겠습니다.
Thank you, sir.
감사합니다.
Director Han.
한 감독.
We're executing official duties.
우리는 공식적인 임무를 수행하고 있습니다.
Please step aside.
비켜주세요.
[text]
[텍스트]
This isn't the Wild West.
이것은 와일드 웨스트가 아닙니다.
What the hell are you doing here?
도대체 여기서 뭐하는 거야?
We have a search and seizure warrant for the S Group chairman's office
우리에겐 수색 및 압수 영장이 있습니다 S그룹 회장실
and the Future Strategy Office.
미래전략실.
Fine.
괜찮은.
You insist on doing this by the book?
당신은 책에 따라 이것을 고집합니까?
The chairman's office is on the 52nd floor, the Future Strategy Office on the 47th.
회장실은 52층에 있고, 47일 미래전략실.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
[text]
[텍스트]
- Is this blocked too? - Yes, take this way.
- 이것도 막혔나요? - 네, 이쪽으로 가세요.
Petty.
자그마한.
Right here.
바로 여기입니다.
It's for the chairman only.
회장님 전용입니다.
Geez.
이런.
I don't even have the key.
열쇠도 없어요.
Let's take a breather.
잠시 숨을 쉬자.
If we miss even one piece of paper, we're screwed.
종이 한장이라도 놓치면 우리는 망했어.
It's fine. Relax.
괜찮습니다. 안심하다.
- Got a cigarette? - What?
- 담배 있어요? - 무엇?
[text]
[텍스트]
By the way, didn't they say the prosecutor was a woman?
그건 그렇고, 그들이 말하지 않았나요? 검사가 여자였어?
[30 minutes earlier]
[30분 전]
2035-Na-9722.
2035-Na-9722.
We will begin the industrial accident damages trial against Gojin Chemical.
산업재해를 시작하겠습니다 고진화학을 상대로 손해배상 재판.
Ms. Han Na Young and [Han Na Young, Plaintiff from Gojin Chemical]
한나영씨와 [고진화학 원고 한나영]
twenty-four employees who worked at Gojin Chemical's Yeoju plant...
24명의 직원이 근무했습니다. 고진화학 여주공장..
have been diagnosed with acute leukemia and brain tumors.
급성 백혈병과 뇌종양 진단을 받았습니다.
Also, nine have already died.
또한 이미 9명이 사망했습니다.
All of them were young,
다들 젊었고,
in their twenties or early thirties.
20대나 30대 초반.
Counsel for the plaintiffs,
원고 측 변호인은,
do you have anything new beyond what we already know?
새로운 거 있어? 우리가 이미 알고 있는 것 이상으로?
What?
무엇?
Your Honor,
재판장님,
Gojin Chemical's work sites are
고진화학의 사업장은
fully sealed to prevent
방지하기 위해 완전히 밀봉
any hazardous substances from entering.
유해 물질이 들어가지 않도록 하세요.
[Song Na Yeon, Judicial Affairs Reporter from Daejin Daily]
[송나연, 대진일보 법무부 기자]
Leukemia can develop from even minimal exposure
백혈병이 발생할 수 있습니다 최소한의 노출이라도
to benzene or formaldehyde.
벤젠이나 포름알데히드로.
This is just a one-sided claim by the plaintiffs.
이건 일방적인 주장일뿐 원고에 의해.
Both sides are noted.
양쪽 모두 주목됩니다.
Counsel for the defense,
변호인단,
you filed a motion for an expert opinion
전문가 의견 신청을 제출하셨습니다
on the link between Gojin Chemical's work environment
사이의 링크에서 고진화학의 작업환경
and the workers' leukemia, correct?
그리고 노동자 백혈병 맞죠?
Yes.
예.
We recommend
우리는 추천합니다
Professor Kim Seok Hyun of Hankuk University
한국대학교 김석현 교수
as the court-appointed expert.
법원이 지정한 전문가로.
We'd like... [Go Jin Gyu, CEO of Gojin Chemical]
우리는... [고진규 고진케미칼 대표]
Gwangmin Law Firm to handle the defense.
법무법인 광민이 변호를 맡습니다.
Well...
음...
I happen to be the head of Haenal Law Firm.
저는 공교롭게도 해날법무법인의 대표입니다.
I'm well aware your son-in-law is a sitting judge.
나는 당신의 사위를 잘 알고 있습니다 현직 판사입니다.
Cases he oversees
그가 감독하는 사건
are often handled by Gwangmin,
종종 광민이 다루는 일
a firm Haenal set up under another name.
다른 이름으로 설립된 해날회사
This trial is...
이 재판은...
a matter of life and death for Gojin Chemical.
삶과 죽음의 문제 고진화학
Former judges are useful,
전직 판사가 유용합니다.
but a sitting judge is even better, right?
하지만 현직 판사가 더 낫지 않나요?
Gojin Chemical is...
고진화학은...
really lucky.
정말 운이 좋았습니다.
Nine are already dead,
9명은 이미 죽었고,
and twenty-four have leukemia.
그리고 24명은 백혈병을 앓고 있습니다.
We agreed on a partial win for the plaintiffs,
우리는 원고의 부분적인 승리에 동의했습니다.
so pay a reasonable amount and wrap it up.
합리적인 금액을 지불하고 마무리하세요.
Okay.
알겠습니다.
A partial win for the plaintiffs?
원고의 부분 승리?
Yes.
예.
As long as it looks like the company made some effort,
그렇게 보이는 한 회사에서는 약간의 노력을 기울였습니다.
that should be fine.
괜찮을 것 같아요.
It'll hurt the company's image,
회사 이미지에 타격을 줄 수 있습니다.
and sales will drop.
판매가 감소할 것입니다.
But if the plaintiffs' claims are dismissed outright,
그러나 원고의 주장이 다음과 같은 경우 완전히 해고되었습니다.
the blame will fall on the court.
책임은 법원에 있습니다.
The additional cost is three hundred million in bearer bonds.
추가 비용은 다음과 같습니다. 무기명 채권 3억
Oh.
아.
You're bolder than your father-in-law.
당신은 시아버지보다 더 대담합니다.
Send it by courier.
택배로 보내주세요.
But still,
하지만 그래도
is this really appropriate for a judge?
이것이 정말 판사에게 적합한가요?
That's exactly why I can do this.
바로 이것이 제가 이 일을 할 수 있는 이유입니다.
[Lee Han Young]
[이한영]
People say he is his in-laws' lapdog.
사람들은 그가 시댁의 반려견이라고 말합니다.
He is a snake.
그는 뱀이다.
There are companies that chew up their workers.
회사가 있어요 직원들을 질식시키는 것입니다.
What's wrong with a judge like this?
이런 판사가 뭐가 문제인가요?
The research team's tests show
연구팀의 테스트 결과
all hazardous substances from Gojin Chemical's Yeoju plant
모든 유해물질 고진화학 여주공장에서
were below legal limits.
법적 한도 미만이었습니다.
Court-appointed expert,
법원이 지정한 전문가,
can you say the test conditions fully matched
테스트 조건이 완전히 일치한다고 말할 수 있나요?
the plaintiffs' working conditions?
원고의 근무 조건은?
Well... I can't say
글쎄...말할 수 없어
they matched one hundred percent.
백퍼센트 일치했어요.
But as a researcher,
하지만 연구자로서,
I took the conditions at the time into full account
조건을 걸었어요 당시 전체 계정에
and did my best.
그리고 최선을 다했습니다.
Any errors in the testing or other possibilities?
테스트 중 오류가 있는 경우 아니면 다른 가능성?
Less than one percent.
1% 미만입니다.
[text]
[텍스트]
What's going on?
무슨 일이야?
[Choi Jong Hak, CEO, S Construction]
[최종학, S건설 대표이사]
What?
무엇?
Why is the prosecution here?
검찰이 왜 여기에?
Damn it.
젠장.
Sir. We've got a problem.
선생님. 문제가 생겼습니다.
- Wait. - Prosecutors...
- 기다리다. - 검찰..
You can't just barge in like this.
이렇게 그냥 끼어들 수는 없어요.
This is Prosecutor Kim Jin Ah,
김진아 검사입니다.
from the Special Division of the Seoul Central Prosecutors' Office.
특별부서 출신 서울중앙검찰청.
We're beginning a search and seizure of S Construction.
검색을 시작하고 있습니다 S건설 압수.
Chairman Jang Tae Sik,
장태식 회장,
this must be quite a shock.
이건 꽤 충격이겠군요.
I'm Prosecutor Kim Jin Ah from the Central District.
김진아 검사입니다 중앙 지구에서.
Long time no see.
오랜만이군요.
We'll meet soon.
곧 만나겠습니다.
Yeah, soon.
응, 곧.
[Search and Seizure Warrant]
[수색 및 압수영장]
I'm out of breath.
숨이 막힌다.
[Jang Tae Sik, Chairman, S Group]
[장태식, S그룹 회장]
What's the password?
비밀번호는 무엇입니까?
What?
무엇?
1-1-0-4-5-6.
1-1-0-4-5-6.
Mr. Kim Yong Jin, please come out.
김용진씨, 나오세요.
The plaintiffs' claim that
원고의 주장은 다음과 같다.
hazardous substances in the work environment
작업 환경의 유해 물질
caused the illnesses
질병을 일으켰다
fails to establish a clear causal link.
명확한 인과관계를 확립하지 못합니다.
The court orders.
법원이 명령합니다.
The plaintiffs' claims are... dismissed.
원고들의 주장은... 기각됩니다.
What does that mean?
그게 무슨 뜻이에요?
Dismissed means what, exactly?
해고란 정확히 무엇을 의미하나요?
Not just no wrongdoing, but no crime.
범죄가 없을 뿐만 아니라 범죄도 없습니다.
- Not guilty. - What did you say?
- 무죄예요. - 뭐라고 하셨나요?
Not guilty?
무죄인가요?
How can they be not guilty?
그들이 어떻게 무죄일 수 있겠습니까?
My child worked there
우리 아이가 거기서 일했어요
and came down with a deadly illness.
그리고 치명적인 병에 걸렸습니다.
How is the owner not guilty?
주인이 어떻게 죄가 없나요?
How is he innocent?
그는 어떻게 결백합니까?
How is he...
그 사람은 어때요...
What kind of heartless law is this?
이 얼마나 무정한 법입니까?
How are we supposed to live with this injustice?
우리는 어떻게 살아야 할까요? 이 불의로?
I can't live with this.
나는 이것으로 살 수 없습니다.
My goodness.
이럴 수가.
Oh, no.
안 돼.
Hey.
여기요.
Na Young.
나영.
You're bleeding.
피가 나고 있어요.
What do we do?
우리는 무엇을 합니까?
What do we do...
우리는 무엇을합니까 ...
Grandma...
할머니...
I'm so sorry.
정말 죄송해요.
Oh, my child.
아, 얘야.
Na Young.
나영.
My poor child...
불쌍한 내 아이...
What are we supposed to do...
우리는 무엇을 해야 할까요...
My child...
내 아이...
My poor child.
나의 불쌍한 아이.
I heard you had it dismissed.
해산됐다고 들었습니다.
Why did you do something I never told you to?
왜 뭔가를 했나요? 내가 너한테 말한 적 없어?
Why?
왜?
Just do what you're paid for!
받은 만큼만 하세요!
You think they'll be grateful
당신은 그들이 감사할 것이라고 생각합니다
if you give them more than that?
그 이상을 주면?
They'll just try to cut the fee.
그들은 수수료를 삭감하려고 노력할 것입니다.
I'll be careful.
조심하겠습니다.
He definitely cut a backroom deal with Gojin Chemical.
그는 확실히 밀실 거래를 끊었습니다 고진화학과 함께합니다.
He's got nothing, yet he's greedy as hell.
아무것도 가진 게 없는데도 욕심이 너무 많아요.
Even a lapdog needs ambition to be useful.
랩독이라도 유용해지려면 야망이 필요합니다.
If he has no greed at all,
그 사람이 욕심이 전혀 없다면,
what would you use him for?
당신은 그를 무엇에 사용 하시겠습니까?
I'm Joo Young Ho. I'm in second grade.
저는 주영호입니다. 저는 2학년이에요.
Is this for me?
이게 나한테 맞는 걸까?
Yeah.
응.
Thanks.
감사해요.
I won first place in the race at our school.
우리 학교 경주에서 1등을 했어요.
Wow, that's awesome.
와, 정말 멋지네요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
So... are you a runner?
그럼... 당신은 달리기 선수인가요?
No.
아니요.
Then why are you running so hard...
그럼 왜 그렇게 열심히 달리는 걸까요...
if you're not an athlete?
운동선수가 아니라면?
Pardon?
뭐라고요?
[Judge Lee Han Young Clears Responsibility in Nine Deaths]
[이한영 판사는 명확한 판결을 내렸습니다. 아홉 죽음의 책임]
A 25-year-old woman battling leukemia
백혈병과 투병 중인 25세 여성
had been waiting for legal relief as a victim of an industrial accident.
법적 구제를 기다리고 있었습니다 산업재해 피해자
But the court ruled there was insufficient proof of causation
그러나 법원은 다음과 같이 판결했습니다. 인과관계 입증이 불충분함
and did not hold the company liable.
회사에 책임을 묻지 않았습니다.
That afternoon, she took her own life
그날 오후, 그녀는 스스로 목숨을 끊었습니다.
from the rooftop of a hospital.
병원 옥상에서
This is Choi Ha Young reporting.
최하영입니다.
In hospital security footage in Seoul,
서울 병원 보안 영상
a woman in a wheelchair is seen heading somewhere.
휠체어를 탄 여성은 어딘가로 향하는 걸 봤어요.
She is the late Han Na Young, who developed leukemia
故 한나영입니다. 백혈병에 걸린 사람
while working at Gojin Chemical's Yeoju plant.
고진화학 여주공장에서 근무할 때
Earlier that day,
그날 초,
the Seoul High Court ruled that Gojin Chemical was not responsible.
서울고등법원이 판결을 내렸습니다. 고진화학에서는 책임이 없음을 알려드립니다.
Hours later,
몇 시간 후,
she jumped from the hospital rooftop.
그녀는 병원 옥상에서 뛰어내렸습니다.
Her note says,
그녀의 메모에는 다음과 같이 적혀 있습니다.
"I don't want to be a burden to my grandma...
"부담이 되고 싶지 않아요 할머니께...
who collects scrap anymore."
더 이상 스크랩을 수집하는 사람."
Short but filled with despair,
짧지만 절망으로 가득 차 있습니다.
the message shows
메시지가 표시됩니다
how long she had been waiting for justice under the law.
그녀가 얼마나 오랫동안 기다렸는지 법에 따른 정의를 위해.
Nine people are dead, and they walk free?
9명이 사망했고, 자유롭게 걷는다고?
Is this justice, Your Honor?
이것이 정의입니까, 재판장님?
People driven to desperate deaths...
절박한 죽음에 내몰린 사람들...
The law turns its back again.
법이 다시 등을 돌립니다.
Judge Lee Han Young, does death mean so little to you?
이한영 판사, 죽음이 당신에게 별 의미가 없나요?
A world where victims die and perpetrators are protected.
피해자가 죽는 세상 가해자는 보호됩니다.
Truly heartbreaking.
정말 가슴 아프네요.
Then why are you running so hard...
그럼 왜 그렇게 열심히 달리는 걸까요...
if you're not an athlete?
운동선수가 아니라면?
Yeah...
응...
I really don't know anymore.
나는 더 이상 정말로 모른다.
The additional cost is three hundred million in bearer bonds.
추가비용은 무기명 채권 3억.
Is this really appropriate for a judge?
이것이 과연 판사에게 적합한가?
That's exactly why I can do this.
그것이 바로 내가 이 일을 할 수 있는 이유이다.
Isn't today your mom's birthday?
오늘은 엄마 생신이 아니지?
She called earlier.
그녀는 더 일찍 전화했습니다.
I wondered what was going on. She never calls.
나는 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는지 궁금했습니다. 그녀는 결코 전화하지 않습니다.
Come over here.
이리로 오세요.
She asked how you were.
그녀는 당신이 어떠냐고 물었습니다.
I guess she wants a birthday call from you.
내 생각엔 그 사람이 너한테 생일 전화를 받고 싶어하는 것 같더라.
She could've called you about that.
그녀가 그 문제로 당신에게 전화했을 수도 있어요.
She can't even call her own son,
자기 아들한테도 전화도 못 하고,
so why does she want congratulations?
그렇다면 그녀는 왜 축하를 원하는 걸까요?
I was going to send this...
이거 보내려고 했는데...
Do you really... think this suits my mother?
정말... 이게 우리 엄마한테 어울린다고 생각하세요?
[Yoo Se Hee, Youngest Daughter of Haenal Law Firm]
[유세희 씨, 법무법인 해날 막내딸]
I don't know.
모르겠어요.
Do I really have to think about all that?
정말 그 모든 것에 대해 생각해야합니까?
The receipt's inside, so whatever.
영수증은 안에 있으니 뭐.
If she doesn't like it, she can exchange it or take the cash.
그녀가 그것을 좋아하지 않는다면, 그녀는 그것을 교환하거나 현금을 가져갈 수 있습니다.
Tell her to do whatever she wants.
그녀가 원하는 것은 무엇이든 하라고 말하세요.
Either way, I did my duty as a daughter-in-law.
어쨌든 나는 며느리로서의 의무를 다했다.
Yeah, I know.
응, 알아요.
When it comes to being a daughter-in-law in name only,
존재에 관해서는 이름뿐인 며느리,
you're the best.
당신은 최고입니다.
No!
아니요!
Father!
아버지!
Did my father recognize me?
아버지는 나를 알아보셨나요?
Mother.
어머니.
Happy birthday.
생일 축하해요.
I wondered why...
왜인지 궁금했는데...
my birthday had to fall on a day like today.
내 생일은 오늘 같은 날이어야 했어요.
Maybe it's because you were meant to come.
아마도 당신이 오기로 되어 있었기 때문일 겁니다.
I'm glad you're here.
당신이 여기 있어서 기뻐요.
If you hadn't come,
당신이 오지 않았다면,
I would've gone to you.
나는 당신에게 갔을 것입니다.
Of course I came. It's your birthday.
물론 왔습니다. 당신의 생일이에요.
But where are you going?
그런데 어디로 가시나요?
The granddaughter downstairs took her own life.
아래층에 있던 손녀가 스스로 목숨을 끊었습니다.
They say she vomited blood in court yesterday.
어제 법정에서 피를 토했다고 하더군요.
People are saying...
사람들은 말합니다...
some damn judge...
미친 판사님...
pushed a dying person over the edge.
죽어가는 사람을 가장자리로 밀었습니다.
You know exactly who that damn judge is. Right?
그 빌어먹을 판사가 누구인지는 당신도 정확히 알고 있습니다. 오른쪽?
Let's go.
갑시다.
We should...
우리는 ...
at least apologize to the living.
적어도 살아있는 사람에게는 사과하십시오.
No.
아니요.
I ruled according to the law.
나는 법에 따라 통치했습니다.
So...
그래서...
I have nothing to apologize for.
저는 사과할 것이 없습니다.
You shouldn't go either.
당신도 가지 말아야 해요.
Why?
왜?
Afraid I'll get grabbed by the hair for being that your mom?
머리카락이 잡힐까 봐 그게 네 엄마라서?
You could get hurt for no reason.
이유 없이 다칠 수도 있어요.
- Please don't go. - You...
- 가지 마세요. - 당신은...
Did you really judge that case fairly?
정말 그 사건을 공정하게 판단하셨나요?
Yes.
예.
Well...
음...
This isn't something you figure out
이건 네가 알아낼 수 있는 게 아니야
by arguing it out.
그것을 주장함으로써.
If you're human, you just know.
당신이 인간이라면, 당신은 단지 알고 있습니다.
Still...
아직도...
if you were truly fair,
당신이 정말 공정했다면,
look me in the eye and say it again.
내 눈을 똑바로 바라보고 다시 말해주세요.
Like, "Mom."
"엄마" 같은 거죠.
"I judged the case fairly."
"나는 이 사건을 공정하게 판단했다."
"I am a fair judge."
"나는 공정한 판사다."
Then I'll believe you
그럼 난 당신을 믿을게요
and stand by you no matter what.
무슨 일이 있어도 당신 편에 서십시오.
"My son is not some damn judge."
"내 아들은 빌어먹을 판사가 아니다."
"He's an upright judge, fair under heaven."
"그분은 의로운 재판관이시며 하늘 아래 공정하신 분이십니다."
So if anyone dares badmouth my son,
그러므로 누구든지 내 아들아, 감히 욕설을 하면
I won't let it slide.
나는 그것이 미끄러지도록 놔두지 않을 것이다.
How did my son end up like this?
내 아들이 어쩌다가 이렇게 됐지?
Mom...
엄마...
If my child did something wrong,
내 아이가 잘못을 했다면,
then as his mother, I should be the one to answer for it.
그러면 그의 어머니로서 나는 그것에 답하는 사람이 되어야 한다.
Mom...
엄마...
Welcome, my dear Chief Justice.
사랑하는 대법원장님, 환영합니다.
Please come in.
들어오세요.
[Kang Shin Jin, Chief Justice]
[강신진 대법원장]
That crazy witch, Kim Jin Ah
그 미친 마녀 김진아
cleaned out S Group's coffers.
S그룹의 금고를 털었습니다.
I'll take care of it.
내가 처리할게.
It won't be free. Right?
그것은 무료가 아닙니다. 오른쪽?
Isn't this costing more than it's worth?
이거 생각보다 비용이 많이 드는거 아닌가요?
You said it was the group's coffers.
그룹의 금고라고 하더군요.
Alright. I get it.
괜찮은. 알겠습니다.
This is Kang Shin Jin.
강신진 입니다.
Hello, Chief Justice.
안녕하세요, 대법원장님.
You know S Group is in trouble.
S그룹이 위기에 처해 있다는 걸 아시죠?
What about Judge Lee Han Young?
이한영 판사는 어떻습니까?
If you assign the case to him,
그 사람에게 사건을 맡기면
he is perfect.
그는 완벽해요.
We'll remove anything
우리는 무엇이든 제거할 것입니다
that could interfere with the trial.
재판에 방해가 될 수도 있으니까요.
I'll hang up now.
이제 전화를 끊겠습니다.
Who is Lee Han Young?
이한영은 누구인가?
He's a judge.
그는 판사입니다.
Haenal Law Firm brought him in as a son-in-law lapdog.
해날법무법인이 그를 데려왔습니다. 사위 랩독으로.
So...
그래서...
he rules however his masters tell him to?
그는 그의 주인이 그에게 지시하는 대로 통치합니까?
A lapdog does what he's told.
랩독은 시키는 대로 합니다.
[Yoo Seon Cheol]
[유선철]
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Now?
지금?
Yes, understood.
네, 이해했습니다.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
He is Judge Lee Han Young,
이한영 판사입니다.
assigned to the S Group case.
S그룹 케이스에 배정되었습니다.
Oh.
오.
I look forward to working with you.
나는 당신과 함께 일하기를 기대합니다.
He is Chairman Jang Tae Sik of S Group.
바로 S그룹 장태식 회장이다.
Nice to meet you.
만나서 반가워요.
So your son is hiding somewhere, and you are here instead?
그래서 당신의 아들은 어딘가에 숨어 있어요. 그런데 당신은 대신 여기 있나요?
If you had any guts, you'd drag that damn judge here.
조금이라도 용기가 있었다면, 그 빌어먹을 판사를 여기로 끌고 가다니.
Why did you come here alone?
왜 여기에 혼자 왔나요?
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Sorry for what?
무슨 일로 미안해요?
If you're really sorry,
정말 미안하다면,
bring your son who handed down
물려준 아들을 데리고 오너라
that acquittal, that dismissal,
그 무죄, 그 해고,
and cut my granddaughter's life short.
그리고 내 손녀의 생명을 단축시켰습니다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Bring my...
내꺼 가져와...
- I'm sorry. - Bring my child back!
- 미안해요. - 내 아이를 다시 데려오세요!
My poor child...
불쌍한 내 아이...
I'm so sorry.
정말 죄송해요.
Bring her back!
그녀를 다시 데려오세요!
Among the documents the prosecution seized,
검찰이 압수한 서류 중에는
there's the embezzlement of S Construction's funds, correct?
횡령이 있다 S건설 자금 맞죠?
Embezzlement?
도용?
No, that money is all mine.
아니요, 그 돈은 모두 내 것입니다.
There are also documents showing slush funds
비자금을 보여주는 문서도 있다
created using embezzled company money.
회사 자금을 횡령하여 만든 것입니다.
So?
그래서?
Slush funds and embezzlement...
비자금·횡령…
If the head of S Construction takes the fall for both,
S건설 사장이라면 둘 다 추락합니다.
there won't be a problem.
문제 없을 겁니다.
So that's what needs to be removed.
그래서 제거해야 하는 것입니다.
Pour him a drink.
그에게 술을 부어주세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Is it okay for a judge to pour me a drink?
판사가 나에게 술을 부어도 괜찮습니까?
In this room, he is not a judge.
이 방에서 그는 판사가 아닙니다.
He is with Haenal Law Firm.
법무법인 해날에 있습니다.
Yeah.
응.
Here.
여기.
Hey.
여기요.
Sir, cardiac arrest!
선생님, 심정지!
- Starting CPR now! - Okay.
- 지금부터 심폐소생술을 시작하세요! - 좋아요.
Yeah, it's ready.
응, 준비 됐어.
[Supreme Court]
[대법원]
Make sure the S Group case...
S그룹 사례를 확인해보세요..
gets assigned to Judge Lee Han Young.
이한영 판사에게 배정됩니다.
Things are a bit noisy right now,
지금 상황이 좀 시끄러워요.
with the Gojin Chemical victim's death.
고진화학 피해자 사망으로.
Also, he's on leave after his mother passed. [Kim Jin Han, Justice]
게다가 어머니가 돌아가신 후 휴가 중이다. [저스티스 김진한]
Once he's back,
그가 돌아오면,
we'll transfer him to Criminal Division
그를 형사과로 이송하겠습니다
and finalize the assignment.
그리고 과제를 마무리합니다.
What about the head of S Construction?
S건설 대표는 어떻습니까?
It'll be taken care of tomorrow.
내일 처리될 예정입니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Public fund embezzlement, and slush fund records...
공금횡령, 그리고 비자금 기록...
it's all in here.
모든 것이 여기에 있습니다.
Illegal loans from financial institutions,
금융기관으로부터의 불법대출,
and bribery charges too.
그리고 뇌물수수 혐의도요.
If you take all of this alone,
이걸 혼자 다 가져가면
you'll be making your own coffin in prison.
당신은 감옥에서 관을 직접 만들게 될 것입니다.
If you keep holding out,
계속 버티다 보면,
do you think Chairman will send you a lifeline?
의장이 당신에게 생명줄을 보내줄 것 같나요?
I doubt it.
나는 그것을 의심한다.
He's probably deciding right now
아마 지금 당장 결정하고 있을 거야
whether to send down a coffin made of paulownia
오동나무 관을 보내야 할지 말지
or one made of cedar.
또는 삼나무로 만든 것.
You should think about your family.
가족에 대해 생각해야합니다.
Deputy Chief.
부국장.
What is it now?
지금은 무엇입니까?
Presiding Judge Lee Han Young
재판장 이한영
is transferring to the Criminal Division.
형사과로 이관됩니다.
What?
무엇?
Who?
WHO?
You haven't heard about him?
그 사람에 대해 들어본 적 없나요?
Looks like S group pulled some strings.
S그룹이 뭔가 끈을 뽑은 것 같네요.
Really?
정말?
Dig into it. Now.
그것을 파헤쳐보세요. 지금.
Yes.
예.
Have some.
좀 드세요.
Please.
제발.
It'll get cold.
추울 거예요.
You don't need to worry about your family.
가족에 대해 걱정할 필요가 없습니다.
I'm just saying it'll be harder if you refuse.
거절하면 더 힘들어진다는 뜻이에요.
In detention.
구금 중.
Not here.
여기는 아닙니다.
Hello, sir.
안녕하세요, 선생님.
So you start at the Criminal Division
그럼 형사부부터 시작해볼까요?
of the Seoul Central District Court tomorrow?
내일 서울중앙지방법원은요?
Yeah, right.
응, 맞아.
All right.
괜찮은.
Come to think of it,
생각해보면,
Yoo Seon Cheol of Haenal Law Firm
법무법인 해날 유선철 변호사
seems to care about you quite a lot.
당신을 꽤 많이 걱정하는 것 같아요.
He's from a regional university, and his training ranking was average.
그 사람은 지방대학교 출신이고, 그의 훈련 순위는 평균이었습니다.
The year he started handling cases solo,
그가 혼자 사건을 처리하기 시작한 해,
he married into Haenal Law Firm.
법무법인 해날과 결혼했습니다.
From then on,
그때부터
a front law firm Haenal set up,
프론트 법률회사 해날을 설립하고,
Gwangmin Law Firm, has a one-hundred-percent win rate.
법무법인 광민, 백퍼센트의 승률을 가지고 있습니다.
They were all Judge Lee Han Young's cases.
모두 이한영 판사의 사건이다.
They didn't gain a son-in-law.
그들은 사위를 얻지 못했습니다.
They gained an ally.
그들은 동맹을 얻었습니다.
That's probably why
아마도 그 이유는
he was the first in his class to make presiding judge.
그 사람이 반에서 첫 번째였어 재판장을 삼는다.
What a bastard.
이런 개자식.
But aside from the Gwangmin cases,
하지만 광민 사건을 제외하면,
his other rulings are considered fairly balanced.
그의 다른 판결도 고려된다 상당히 균형이 잡혔습니다.
So not a complete bastard?
그럼 완전 개자식 아닌가?
Lee Han Young's father has dementia.
이한영의 아버지는 치매를 앓고 있다.
He's in a nursing facility in Gwacheon.
과천 요양시설에 있어요.
Wow...
와우...
Do you know how much a year there costs?
1년에 얼마의 비용이 드는지 아시나요?
Two hundred million won.
2억 원.
The payments are from Yoo Se Hee.
결제는 유세희님이 하셨습니다.
It's Lee Han Young's wife.
이한영 아내입니다.
Looks like he benefits plenty from his in-laws,
그는 시댁으로부터 많은 혜택을 받는 것 같습니다.
but there's nothing in his own name.
하지만 그 사람 이름으로는 아무것도 없어요.
He must be stashing it somewhere.
그는 그것을 어딘가에 숨겨두었을 것입니다.
Any women? Gambling? Anything else?
여자 있나요? 도박? 다른 건 없나요?
He's a judge Haenal Law Firm has on a leash.
법무법인 해날이 묶여 있는 판사입니다.
We need at least one weakness.
적어도 하나의 약점이 필요합니다.
He's got two nicknames.
그는 별명이 두 개 있어요.
One is "the in-laws' lapdog."
하나는 '시댁의 랩독'입니다.
Ever seen servants get paid
하인이 돈을 받는 걸 본 적 있어
when the masters make deals?
주인이 거래를 할 때?
No woman trouble. No gambling either.
여자 문제는 없습니다. 도박도 안 됩니다.
Among bastards,
멍청이들 사이에서는
he's the obedient kind.
그는 순종적인 사람이에요.
Anything else?
다른 건 없나요?
You said two nicknames.
별명이 두 개라고 하더군요.
Six-dot.
여섯 점.
"Six-dot?"
"6점?"
Sounds like gambling.
도박처럼 들리네요.
No, he doesn't gamble.
아니요, 그는 도박을 하지 않습니다.
It's because he clocks out at six, sharp.
그 이유는 그가 6시에 출근하기 때문이죠.
Is that even possible for a Korean judge?
한국 판사에게도 그게 가능할까요?
Yes. He's Haenal's son-in-law.
그렇습니다. 해날의 사위입니다.
That's why his caseload is...
그래서 그의 업무량이...
kept reasonable.
합리적으로 유지
Looks like you'll have to find his weakness yourself, sir.
찾아야 할 것 같습니다 그의 약점은 당신 자신입니다.
Hang up.
끊으세요.
Hey, Number 522!
안녕하세요, 522호입니다!
Wake up!
깨우다!
What?
무엇?
How the hell...
도대체 어떻게...
did you botch the surveillance?
감시를 망쳤어?
What do we do?
우리는 무엇을 하나요?
If this gets out, they'll scream coercive investigation.
이게 나오면 강압수사를 외칠 것이다.
Should we slap an embargo on the legal reporters first?
금수 조치를 취해야 할까요? 먼저 법률 기자부터요?
No.
아니요.
Leak it as a tip from a prosecution source,
검찰 관계자 제보로 유출해
that homicide is a possibility.
살인이 가능하다는 것입니다.
Then one of them will come begging to save themselves.
그러면 그 중 한 명이 올 것이다. 자신을 구해달라고 간청합니다.
[50 million won]
[5천만원]
Han Young?
한영?
My dear son.
내 사랑하는 아들.
You have to be a judge.
당신은 판사가되어야합니다.
I became a judge a long time ago.
나는 판사가 된 지 꽤 됐다.
Why are you still saying that?
왜 아직도 그런 말을 하는 거야?
I don't even know if I became a judge the way you wanted.
나도 모르겠어 내가 당신이 원하는 대로 판사가 된다면요.
Your son is so kind.
당신의 아들은 정말 친절해요.
You're Judge Lee Han Young, right?
이한영 판사 맞죠?
I'm Prosecutor Kim Jin Ah...
저는 김진아 검사입니다...
from the Special Division of the Seoul Central Prosecutors' Office.
특수부 출신 서울중앙검찰청.
We'll be seeing each other in court soon.
우리는 곧 법정에서 다시 뵙게 될 것입니다.
You know, Chairman Jang Tae Sik of S Group...
S그룹 장태식 회장님...
I'll be indicting him.
나는 그를 기소할 것이다.
I stirred up S Group's reservoir,
S그룹 저수지를 휘저었고,
and it looks like people up top panicked.
그리고 꼭대기에 있는 사람들이 당황한 것 같습니다.
They even pulled a judge from the High Court's civil division
그들은 심지어 판사를 뽑았어 고등법원 민사부
into the criminal division.
범죄 부문으로.
Fine. You can play dumb.
괜찮은. 바보처럼 놀 수 있습니다.
But this time, let's do it by the book.
하지만 이번에는 책대로 해보자.
Otherwise, I'll start with you and tear everything apart.
그렇지 않으면 너부터 시작할게 그리고 모든 것을 찢어 버리십시오.
I graduated second in my class at Hankuk University Law School.
나는 반에서 2등으로 졸업했다 한국대학교 법학전문대학원에서.
I'm smart, and I've got a very nasty temper.
나는 똑똑하고 성격이 매우 고약합니다.
From what I see, you don't look that smart.
내가 보기엔, 당신은 그다지 똑똑해 보이지는 않네요.
Then I guess you admit the nasty temper part.
그렇다면 당신은 성격이 나쁜 부분을 인정하는 것 같아요.
If you want to keep living as your in-laws' lapdog,
계속 살고 싶다면 당신의 시댁의 랩독으로서,
let's do it by the book this time.
이번에는 책대로 해보자.
I'll request full transcripts and audio recordings at trial.
전체 대본을 요청하겠습니다 그리고 재판에서의 오디오 녹음.
Don't. I'll deny it.
하지 않다. 나는 그것을 거부할 것이다.
Why?
왜?
Nervous?
불안한?
If you're nervous, you've already lost.
긴장했다면 이미 진 것입니다.
Breaking news.
속보.
Choi Jong Hak, CEO of S Construction, who was under investigation,
최종학 S건설 대표이사, 조사를 받고 있던 사람,
was found unconscious this morning
오늘 아침 의식을 잃은 채로 발견되었습니다
while in custody at the Seoul Detention Center.
서울구치소에 구금되어 있는 동안
He was rushed to the hospital
그는 병원으로 급히 이송되었습니다
but was later pronounced dead.
그러나 나중에 사망한 것으로 판명되었습니다.
Police are currently investigating the case,
현재 경찰이 해당 사건을 조사하고 있습니다.
with suicide considered the leading possibility.
자살을 고려한 경우 가능성이 높습니다.
Given that Choi was a key figure in the prosecution's investigation...
최씨가 핵심 인물이었던 점을 감안하면 검찰 수사에…
CEO Choi Jong Hak...
최종학 대표...
didn't kill himself.
자살하지 않았습니다.
There is growing speculation about
에 대한 추측이 커지고 있습니다
outside pressure or possible third-party involvement.
외부 압력 또는 제3자가 개입할 가능성이 있습니다.
Prosecutors have seized internal off-the-books ledgers,
검찰이 압수수색했습니다. 내부 장부 장부
revealing illegal fund flows worth trillions of won...
불법자금 흐름을 폭로하는 행위 수조원의 가치가 있는...
Did you get anything out of him?
그 사람에게서 얻은 게 있나요?
No.
아니요.
I just warned him.
방금 그에게 경고했어요.
Didn't seem to work.
작동하지 않는 것 같았습니다.
You should've at least blown up at him.
최소한 그 사람한테 화를 냈어야 했는데.
Yeah.
응.
I'm already regretting it.
벌써 후회하고 있어요.
Sir,
선생님,
can we expect a fair trial today?
오늘 공정한 재판을 기대할 수 있을까요?
Will the death of the S Construction CEO
S건설 CEO 사망할까
affect the ruling?
판결에 영향을 미치나요?
Sir,
선생님,
just one comment please...
댓글 하나만 부탁드려요...
Please step back.
뒤로 물러서주세요.
Please, sir.
부탁드립니다.
The prosecution is targeting
검찰은 표적
Chairman Jang Tae Sik of S Group
S그룹 장태식 회장
over embezzlement, slush funds, and improper lobbying with banks.
횡령, 비자금, 그리고 은행과의 부적절한 로비.
The court will rule fairly,
법원은 공정하게 판결할 것이며,
based on the law and the facts.
법률과 사실에 근거하여.
Please step back.
뒤로 물러서주세요.
Just one word, sir.
한마디만 해주세요 선생님.
Hello, Justice.
안녕하세요, 정의님.
You were appointed the same time as him?
당신도 그 사람과 같은 시기에 임명되었나요?
[Kim Yun Hyeok, Presiding Judge]
[부장판사 김윤혁]
Yes.
그렇습니다.
Are you two close?
둘이 친해요?
We're on decent terms.
우리는 좋은 관계를 유지하고 있습니다.
Good.
좋은.
Aren't you curious...
궁금하지 않나요...
who killed the S Construction CEO?
S건설 CEO를 죽인 사람은 누구인가?
It was because of prosecutorial coercion, right?
때문이었습니다 검찰강제 맞죠?
Some say he was driven to suicide.
어떤 사람들은 그가 자살을 했다고도 합니다.
Then you should be out catching the killer.
그럼 살인자를 잡으러 나가야 해.
What's the point?
요점은 무엇입니까?
The court can just acquit him anyway.
법원은 어쨌든 그에게 무죄를 선고할 수 있습니다.
As long as you follow the law,
법을 준수하는 한,
I'd beg on my knees if I had to.
필요하다면 무릎을 꿇고 빌겠습니다.
Oh, right.
아, 그렇죠.
Not you.
당신은 아닙니다.
I should do that to Yoo Seon Cheol at Haenal Law Firm.
유선철한테 그랬어야지 법무법인 해날에서.
Are you out of your mind?
정신이 나갔나요?
These are the records of...
이것들은 다음의 기록입니다...
Chairman Jang Tae Sik's embezzlement and slush funds.
장태식 회장의 횡령 및 비자금.
[Kim Yong Jin, Accounting Director of S Construction]
[김용진 씨, S건설 회계이사]
They say you're obsessed with indicting S Group.
그들은 당신이 집착하고 있다고 말합니다 S그룹을 기소합니다.
Is that a prosecutor's duty,
그게 검찰의 의무인가,
or a personal grudge?
아니면 개인적인 원한?
Both.
둘 다.
I went after Jang Tae Sik the moment I became a prosecutor.
장태식을 쫓아갔어 검사가 된 순간.
You have impure motives.
당신은 불순한 동기를 가지고 있습니다.
Let's grab lunch.
점심을 먹자.
I'm busy.
나는 바쁘다.
This is complicated to handle, isn't it?
처리하기가 복잡하지 않습니까?
Not really.
설마.
Anything I can help with?
제가 도와드릴 게 있나요?
You'll miss lunch.
점심을 놓칠 거예요.
What about the ruling?
판결은 어떻습니까?
Yes.
예.
The S Group's trial date is the day after tomorrow...
S그룹의 재판일은 모레...
So,
그래서,
the draft ruling should be ready by now.
지금쯤 판결 초안이 준비됐을 겁니다.
I'll check it at his lunch.
점심시간에 확인해 보겠습니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
You still here?
아직 여기 있나요?
I'm heading out now.
나는 지금 나가고 있다.
He is from a no-name school with zero connections...
그 사람은 이름없는 학교 출신이야 연결이 전혀 없습니다 ...
Why did Haenal Law Firm pick a guy like that?
법무법인 해날이 왜 그랬나요? 그런 남자를 골라?
I'm way better than him.
나는 그 사람보다 훨씬 낫습니다.
It looks like the ruling on Chairman Jang isn't ready yet.
에 대한 판결인 것 같습니다. 장 회장은 아직 준비가 안 됐다.
I'm kind of nervous.
좀 긴장되네요.
Finally...
드디어...
Are you heading to Haenal Law Firm?
법무법인 해날에 가시나요?
Mr. Yoo,
미스터. 유,
it's me.
나야.
Judge Lee Han Young submitted his resignation.
이한영 판사가 사표를 제출했습니다.
I thought you should know.
당신이 알아야 한다고 생각했어요.
Let's get dinner.
저녁을 먹자.
Can't you eat without me?
나 없으면 밥 못 먹어?
Not me.
나는 아니다.
With the Justice.
정의와 함께.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
There's a senior judicial research clerk at the Supreme Court
고위 사법연구관이 있어요 대법원에서
whose term is ending soon.
임기가 곧 끝난다.
Once that seat opens, it has to be filled immediately.
그 자리가 열리면, 즉시 채워야 합니다.
That's unfortunate.
불행한 일이군요.
If I'd known earlier, I wouldn't have resigned.
미리 알았더라면 사임하지 않았을 텐데.
You resigned?
사임하셨나요?
After work, I stopped by the chief judge's office.
퇴근 후, 나는 대법원장실에 들렀다.
Did Yoo Seon Cheol approve it?
유선철님이 승인하셨나요?
Do you really think...
정말 그렇게 생각하시나요...
Yoo Seon Cheol approved?
유선철 승인?
By now,
지금쯤이면,
he probably knows.
그는 아마도 알고 있을 것이다.
Your resignation won't be accepted for the time being.
당신의 사임은 받아들여지지 않을 것입니다 당분간.
Chief Justice Kang Shin Jin
강신진 대법원장
is very interested in this case.
이 사건에 매우 관심이 있습니다.
The Supreme Court is bigger than it looks from the outside.
대법원은 그보다 더 크다. 그것은 외부에서 보입니다.
If you don't like the research post,
연구글이 마음에 들지 않는다면,
decide what you do want.
당신이 원하는 것을 결정하십시오.
While you prepare for the S Group trial.
S그룹 재판을 준비하는 동안
The prosecution will reassign the case after the first trial,
검찰, 사건을 재수사할 예정 첫 번째 재판 이후,
and a different prosecutor will handle the appeal.
그리고 다른 검사가 항소를 처리하십시오.
But...
하지만...
Judge Lee Han Young is the problem.
문제는 이한영 판사다.
He turned down a Supreme Court post...
대법원 직위도 거절했다…
and resigned.
그리고 사임했다.
Did he change that fast?
그 사람이 그렇게 빨리 변했나요?
This is getting messy.
점점 지저분해지고 있어요.
Hello, sir.
안녕하세요, 선생님.
Looks like your son-in-law lacks respect for his father-in-law.
사위가 부족한 것 같군요 시아버지에 대한 존경심.
[Haenal Law Firm]
[법무법인 해날]
Sit.
앉아.
Do you only use your mouth in court?
법정에서는 입만 사용하시나요?
No greeting at all? Like, "Sir, how have you been?"
인사가 전혀 없나요? "선생님, 그동안 잘 지내셨나요?"
Oh.
오.
Is it because I'm younger than you?
내가 너보다 어려서 그런 걸까?
Hello, sir.
안녕하세요, 선생님.
See? Much nicer.
보다? 훨씬 더 좋습니다.
A family greeting keeps things nice and friendly.
가족 인사말은 계속됩니다 친절하고 좋은 것.
So, did you resign?
그래서 사임하셨나요?
Yes.
예.
Finish the S Group case,
S그룹 사건을 마무리하고,
then come back.
그럼 다시 오세요.
No. I'm going independent.
아뇨. 저는 독립할 거예요.
Father, did you hear that?
아버지, 그거 들으셨어요?
Did another firm make you an offer?
다른 회사에서 제안을 했나요?
That'd be interesting.
흥미로울 것 같아요.
Haenal's son-in-law working at another firm.
해날의 사위는 다른 회사에 다니고 있다.
No.
아니요.
Nothing like that.
그런 건 없어요.
We'll talk later.
나중에 얘기하자.
Presiding Judge Lee Han Young.
재판장 이한영.
This is for you.
이것은 당신을 위한 것입니다.
What is this?
이게 뭔가요?
The final ruling in the S Group case.
S그룹 사건 최종 판결.
A judge's robe represents...
판사의 예복은...
authority entrusted...
권한 위임...
by the people.
사람들에 의해.
From now on,
지금부터
Haenal Law Firm's power
법무법인 해날의 힘
will stand behind that authority.
그 권위를 지지할 것입니다.
It's been ten years.
10년이 지났습니다.
Living like a dog...
개처럼 살아..
on Haenal's leash.
해날의 목줄에.
Now...
지금...
you're forcing the ruling too?
너도 판결을 강요하는 거야?
Finish this case...
이 사건을 마무리하세요...
and come back.
그리고 돌아오세요.
I'll go independent.
저는 독립하겠습니다.
What changes if you're still Haenal's son-in-law?
가만히 있으면 무엇이 달라지나요? 해날의 사위요?
Then I'll divorce.
그럼 이혼하겠습니다.
Father.
아버지.
That's why you don't let a lapdog taste money.
그렇기 때문에 당신은 허락하지 않습니다 랩독은 돈을 맛본다.
Lapdog...
랩독...
Whatever you do,
당신이 무엇을 하든,
not until the S Group trial is over.
S그룹 재판이 끝날 때까지.
Understand?
이해하다?
My dealings with Haenal Law Firm
법무법인 해날과의 거래
end here.
여기서 끝.
Should we have a kid?
우리 아이를 가져야 하나?
I'm not saying I'll carry one.
나는 하나를 가지고 갈 것이라고 말하지 않습니다.
Just bring one from somewhere.
그냥 어디에서나 하나 가져오세요.
Let's get divorced.
이혼하자
You seeing someone?
누군가를 만나고 있나요?
Just bring a kid.
그냥 아이를 데려오세요.
If you don't have one, start trying now.
가지고 있지 않다면 지금 시도해 보세요.
A daughter would be nice.
딸이 있으면 좋을 것 같아요.
I told your father.
내가 네 아버지한테 말했잖아.
You can't divorce me.
당신은 나와 이혼할 수 없습니다.
Divorce happens...
이혼이 일어난다..
when I decide it does.
내가 결정했을 때.
Don't come home
집에 오지 마세요
until I say...
내가 말할 때까지...
you can.
당신은 할 수 있습니다.
Father.
아버지.
That's why you don't let a lapdog taste money.
이것이 바로 랩독이 돈을 맛보지 못하게 하는 이유입니다.
I lived like a loser.
나는 패배자처럼 살았습니다.
You bastard, just drop dead!
이 개자식아, 그냥 죽어라!
What?
무엇?
Hey.
여기요.
What did you just say?
방금 뭐라고 했어?
- Don't. - Let go!
- 하지 않다. - 놔!
Drop dead, you bastard!
죽어라, 이 개자식아!
You're nothing.
당신은 아무것도 아니다.
Hey!
여기요!
Hey, stop it.
이봐, 그만해.
Stop.
멈추다.
Enough. Come here.
충분한. 이리 오세요.
Let's just go.
그냥 가자.
The granddaughter downstairs took her own life.
아래층에 있는 손녀 스스로 목숨을 끊었습니다.
The plaintiffs' claims are...
원고의 주장은...
Some damn judge...
망할 판사...
- Dismissed. - pushed a dying person over the edge.
- 기각되었습니다. - 죽어가는 사람을 가장자리로 밀었습니다.
Not guilty?
무죄인가요?
How is he innocent?
그 사람은 어떻게 결백한가요?
That's why you don't let a lapdog taste money.
이것이 바로 랩독이 돈을 맛보지 못하게 하는 이유입니다.
What kind of heartless law is this?
이게 무슨 무정한 법인가요?
How are we supposed to live with this injustice?
우리는 어떻게 살아야 하는가 이런 불의를 가지고?
I can't live with this.
난 이걸로 살 수 없어.
How did my son end up like this?
내 아들은 어떻게 된 걸까요?
It's time. Why isn't he here yet?
시간이다. 그 사람은 왜 아직 안 왔어요?
He'll be in any moment.
그는 언제든지 올 것입니다.
If the people taking my money worked like this,
내 돈 가져가는 사람들이 이렇게 일했다면
they'd all be finished.
다 끝났을 텐데.
Of course. I know.
물론. 알아요.
All rise.
모두 일어나세요.
Please be seated.
자리에 앉으시기 바랍니다.
The defendant, Jang Tae Sik,
피고인 장태식은
is merely a victim of
단지 피해자일 뿐이야
the reckless and immoral embezzlement and slush fund schemes
무모하고 부도덕한 횡령 비자금 계획
carried out by S Construction CEO Choi Jong Hak.
S건설에서 진행한 대표이사 최종학.
However,
그러나,
an employee's wrongdoing is...
직원의 잘못은...
ultimately the chairman's responsibility.
결국 회장의 책임이다.
I repent.
나는 회개한다.
For the past ten years,
지난 10년 동안,
the defendant used S Construction
피고는 S건설을 이용하였다
as a vehicle for embezzlement
횡령수단으로
and slush funds.
그리고 비자금.
Also, now seeks to pin his crimes...
그리고 이제 자신의 범죄를 규명하려고 하는데...
on the late CEO Choi Jong Hak.
故 최종학 대표이사.
Accordingly, the prosecution,
이에 검찰은
under the Act on Aggravated Punishment of Specific Economic Crimes,
가중처벌법에 의거 특정경제범죄,
seeks a sentence of...
형을 구한다...
six years in prison
6년의 징역
and a fine of 12 billion won
그리고 벌금 120억 원
for the defendant, Jang Tae Sik.
피고인 장태식.
Don't worry.
괜찮아요.
Defendant, please stand.
피고인은 일어서 주십시오.
The court orders.
법원이 명령합니다.
The defendant, Jang Tae Sik,
피고인 장태식은
is sentenced to ten years in prison
징역 10년을 선고받다
and a fine of 24 billion won.
그리고 벌금 240억 원.
The defendant is taken into custody.
피고인은 구금됩니다.
What? What just happened?
무엇? 방금 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
Did you hear that? Ten years.
그거 들었어? 10년.
Why such a nice ruling?
왜 그렇게 좋은 판결입니까?
Is there anyone to notify of the defendant's detention?
알려줄 사람 있어? 피고인 구금 상태는?
Has he lost his mind?
그 사람이 정신을 잃었나요?
Hey, come down here!
이봐, 여기로 내려와!
- What? Detention? - Please calm down.
- 무엇? 구류? - 진정하세요.
Ten years?
10년?
Let go of me! Are you kidding me?
날 놔줘! 농담하는 거야?
Judge Lee!
이 판사님!
Redo this!
이것을 다시 실행하세요!
Hey!
여기요!
Do you know what you just did?
방금 무슨 짓을 했는지 아세요?
Tell them to appeal.
그들에게 항소하라고 말하세요.
What? This punk.
뭐? 이 새끼야.
What the hell are you doing?
대체 뭐하는 거야?
Ridiculous.
말도 안되는 소리.
Did you want a divorce that badly?
그렇게 이혼하고 싶었나요?
I'll send the papers.
서류를 보내드릴게요.
[Defendant's Seat]
[피고인석]
The defendant, Lee Han Young,
피고인 이한영은
is charged with murdering an accomplice
공범을 살해한 혐의로 기소됐다
and issuing threats.
그리고 위협을 가합니다.
The prosecution hereby brings charges
검찰은 이에 혐의를 적용
against the defendant, Lee Han Young.
피고인 이한영에 대하여.
Defendant,
피고인,
do you admit to the charges?
혐의를 인정합니까?
No. No.
아뇨. 아뇨.
No!
안돼!
Defendant.
피고.
It wasn't me!
내가 아니었어!
No.
아니요.
I...
나는...
I am not guilty.
나는 무죄입니다.
I'm not guilty!
나는 무죄다!
I'll prove my own innocence.
나는 내 결백을 증명할 것이다.
You can't handle this alone.
혼자서 처리할 수는 없습니다.
You piece of trash!
쓰레기 같으니!
This is what happens when trash plays judge!
쓰레기가 판사 역할을 하면 이런 일이 발생합니다!
I finally want to live...
드디어 살고 싶다...
as the real Lee Han Young.
진짜 이한영처럼
2025?
2025년?
I'm back exactly ten years.
저는 정확히 10년 만에 돌아왔습니다.
Kim Sang Jin?
김상진?
Arrest him now. If you don't, that child will die.
지금 그를 체포하세요. 그렇지 않으면 그 아이는 죽을 것이다.
- How do you know that? - Didn't you read the case file?
- 그걸 어떻게 아세요? - 사건 파일을 읽지 않았나요?
You released him.
당신은 그를 석방했습니다.
I have a child.
저에게는 아이가 있습니다.
Right. I'm a judge.
맞습니다. 저는 판사입니다.
Then try Kim Sang Jin with me.
그럼 저와 함께 김상진을 만나보세요
I have to prove he's a serial killer.
그 사람이 연쇄살인범이라는 걸 증명해야 해요.